Guide to the Arnold Sundgaard papers, 1925-1988
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
Arnold Sundgaard papers
1925-1988
C0226
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
19.0 linear feet (46 boxes)
The Arnold Sundgaard papers includes materials created and collected by Arnold Sundgaard. The collection is divided into eight series: Correspondence; Musical Scores; Newspaper Clippings; Photographs; Playscripts; Programs and Posters; Writings, Reviews, Publications; and Audio Recordings.
Sundgaard, Arnold, 1909-2006
Related Material
The Works Progress Administration oral histories collection, the Federal Theatre Project collection, the Federal Theatre Project photograph collection, as well as numerous other personal papers.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Arnold Sundgaard to Special Collections and Archives on October 19, 1978.
Biographical note
Arnold Olaf Sundgaard was born in St. Paul, Minnesota, on October 31, 1909. He studied English at the University of Wisconsin and then drama at Yale University. Sundgaard taught at many colleges including the University of Texas, Columbia University in New York, Bennington College, and at Trinity College in Dublin.
Sundgaard worked for the Chicago Federal Theatre Project and is best known in this context as the writer of the Living Newspaper production Spirochete. He worked with the FTP from 1936 to 1938 as an author and play reader, after which he was let go since he was starting to make a living as a writer. The main theme of Spirochete is the history and spread of syphilis from the 15th century in Europe to the 1930s in America. The play was politically minded and current in relation to the Marriage Test Law of 1937. This Law would require a blood test for syphilis prior to marriage. The play opened in Chicago on April 29, 1938, and had showings in Seattle, Philadelphia, Cincinnati, and Portland, Oregon during February of 1939. Even though the play was met with protest in some areas due to its controversial subject matter, it was the second most performed Living Newspaper play after One-Third of a Nation.
After working with the FTP Sundgaard went on to be a successful writer and librettist. As an author he wrote articles, lyrics, plays, and children's books. To his credit are articles for The New Yorker, and the Atlantic; libretti for Down in the Valley by Kurt Weill, and The Greenfield Christmas Tree; plays such as Giants in the Earth (co-written with Douglas Moore), Everywhere I Roam, the Broadway produced Of Love Remembered, Promised Valley, Forests of the Night, The Great Campaign, and Young Abe Lincoln; children's books include An Axe, an Apple, and a Buckskin Jacket, The Lamb and the Butterfly, and Jethro's Difficult Dinosaur.
Sundgaard died in Dallas, Texas, on October 22, 2006.
Scope and Content
The Arnold Sundgaard papers includes materials created and collected by Arnold Sundgaard. The collection is divided into eight series: Correspondence; Musical Scores; Newspaper Clippings; Photographs; Playscripts; Programs and Posters; Writings, Reviews, Publications; and Audio Recordings. Series are primarily arranged alphabetically by material type and then alphabetically by folder title. Series eight, Audio Recordings, is arranged by size of material.
Series 1, Correspondence, is arranged alphabetically by play title, organization or person. Plays written about include Akron by Moonlight, Down in the Valley, The Beautiful and Anxious Maidens, Equinox, Everywhere I Roam, Forests of the Night, Giants in the Earth, The First Crocus, The Great Campaign, The Kilgo Run, Knock on Wood, and Nobody's Earnest. Persons and organizations included in the correspondence are: The Atlantic Monthly, George P. Baker, Yale, The Barter Theatre, Louis Bellson, Bing Crosby, Lehman Engel, Archibald MacLeish, The New Yorker magazine, Gregory Peck, E. B. White, Alec Wilder, and Thornton Wilder among others.
Series 2, Musical Scores, is arranged alphabetically by title and comprises sheet music and lyrics written by Arnold Sundgaard. Some of the music is published under title of play and some are handwritten music for individual songs. Plays included are: Buddy, Knock on Wood, Of Love Remembered, Promised Valley, Cumberland Fair: A Jamboree, Down in the Valley, Gallantry, Sunday Excursion, The Lowland Sea, The Lonesome Dove. About one-third of the material is in oversize boxes.
Series 3, Newspaper Clippings, is arranged alphabetically by title and includes primarily newspaper and magazine clippings relating to play productions and writings authored by Sundgaard, as well as scrapbooks, programs, ephemera, and some photographs. Two scrapbooks, one about Of Love Remembered, the other about Federal Theatre Project productions, Spirochete and Everywhere I Roam, are housed in oversize boxes.
Series 4, Photographs, is arranged alphabetically by title and includes photographs of play productions, actors, and Arnold Sundgaard. Photographs of play productions include the plays: Brigham, Down in the Valley, Equinox, Everywhere I Roam, Forests of the Night, Giants in the Earth, The Great Campaign, The First Crocus, Kilgo Run, Knock on Wood, Of Love Remembered, The Promised Valley, Spirochete, This Fallow Ground, and The Truth About Windmills. Images are mostly prints; there are some slides, and some oversize material.
Series 5, Playscripts, is arranged alphabetically by title and includes primarily playscripts but also radio and television scripts, libretti, outlines, drafts, production notes, scores, programs, costume designs, and some correspondence. Multiple drafts of produced plays are here, as is unfinished scripts and scripts for plays not produced.
Series 6, Programs and Posters, is arranged alphabetically by title and includes programs and posters for productions written by Sundgaard as well as programs collected by Sundgaard.
Series 7, Writings, Reviews, Publications, is arranged alphabetically by title and includes writings by Sundgaard that are not scripts. The writings include drafts, outlines, articles, essays, and short stories. Both unpublished and published material is included. There are some books. Also present is research material created by Sundgaard for different projects. One project was a syphilis related research project for a possible book that Sundgaard undertook with O.C. Wenger. Another project represented is research of deafness conducted by Sundgaard in Hermann, Missouri.
Series 8, Audio Recordings, is arranged by size and consists of four boxes that include audio cassette tapes, reel-to-reel audio recordings, and vinyl records. The material includes recordings from productions or songs that Sundgaard wrote, and records featuring Sundgaard's children's books.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 8 series based on material type.
Series 1: Correspondence, 1933-1988 (boxes 1-5)
Series 2: Musical Scores, 1947-1982 (boxes 5-6, 44-46)
Series 3: Newspaper Clippings, 1935-1976 (boxes 6-8, 43)
Series 4: Photographs, 1933-1982 (boxes 8, 42, 44)
Series 5: Playscripts, 1932-1978 (boxes 8-21, 42)
Series 6: Programs and Posters, 1925-1988 (boxes 22-29, oversize folder)
Series 7: Writings, Reviews, Publications, 1933-1988 (boxes 29-37, 43, 44)
Series 8: Audio Recordings, 1955-1980s (boxes 38-41)
Alternative Form Available
There are digital documents from this and other GMU FTP collections in the.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Index Terms
Persons:
Sundgaard, Arnold, 1909-2006
Corporate Names:
Federal Theatre Project (U.S.)
Subjects:
New Deal, 1933-1939.; Performing arts.; Playwriting.; Theater--United States.
Contents List
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1933-1988; (boxes 1-5)
  Series 1: Correspondence (1933-1988) is arranged alphabetically by play title, organization or person. Plays written about include Akron by Moonlight, Down in the Valley, The Beautiful and Anxious Maidens, Equinox, Everywhere I Roam, Forests of the Night, Giants in the Earth, The First Crocus, The Great Campaign, The Kilgo Run, Knock on Wood, and Nobody's Earnest. Persons and organizations included in the corresponence are: The Atlantic Monthly, George P. Baker, Yale, The Barter Theatre, Louis Bellson, Bing Crosby, Lehman Engel, Archibald MacLeish, The New Yorker magazine, Gregory Peck, E. B. White, Alec Wilder, and Thornton Wilder among others.
  - Actors studio, Strasberg and Crawford, Gill Crowe, 1962-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Akron by Moonlight correspondence, 1962-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Amarillo Strip, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Roger Ames, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - ASCAP (American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers, 1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - D'Ann Allred, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Apstein and Kayden, 1951-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Includes: Theodore Apstein, Giants in the Earth (1951) to Kilgo Run (1968); letters to Mildred Kayden in London and Spain. Apstein, Kayden and Sundgaard collaborated on a play together - Cortes, correspondence continued with Apstein until 1977.
  - The Atlantic Monthly, 1955-1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Includes: permission to reprint the article "Jazz: Hot and Cold"; "Autumn of a Virgin"; rejection of "The Drifter".
  - The Author's League, October 24, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Correspondence regarding the royalties from Everywhere I Roam.
  - Ethan Ayer (memorial), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - George P. Baker, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Note commenting on Sundgaard's first play at Yale.
  - Barter Theatre, 1979-1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Barter Theatre to Rex Parrington, June 6, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Louis Bellson, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Correspondence regarding music and Seven Joys of Buddy Biloxi.
  - Louis Belson (photocopy), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bennington College, 1949; 1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Vincent C. Brann, University of Massachusetts at Amherst, 1972-1978 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Brigham, 1976-1983 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Brigham Young University, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Kenneth Burke, June 16, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Center for Mass Communication of Columbia University Press, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Schuyler G. Chapin, General Manager, Metropolitan Opera, September 24, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - The Chekov Theatre Studio, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Clifford and Elsa David, November 1973 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Compass Productions, 1961; 1967 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Aaron Copeland, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bing Crosby, October 1957 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Composers: Copeland, Thompson, Lane, Menotti, Rome, Dello Joio, Berstein, 1948-1967 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Dallas Theatre Center, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Gordon Davidson, Center Theatre Group, June-September 1969 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Down in the Valley, (remembering Kurt Weill), 1990 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Dramatist Guild, Inc., 1964-1974 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Correspondence regarding plays, rights, and membership in the Guild.
  - Dramatists Play Service, Inc., January 1952 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Lehman Engel, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Lehman Engel - The Beautiful and Anxious Maidens, 1962-1966 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Equinox, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Everywhere I Roam, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Film suggestions, 1941-1965 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Fionnuala Flanagan, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Five Finger exercise, September 1973-January 1974 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - The Ford Foundation, October 1959 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Forests of the Night, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Forests of the Night, 1965-1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Corresondence with Stephen Murray who appeared in Dublin.
  - Forests of the Night, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Forests of the Night (Louis Lenith, Dublin, Ireland), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Forests of the Night; Of Love Remembered; American Playwright's Theatre, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Forests of the Night; Of Love Remembered; miscellaneous correspondence, 1963-1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Wallace Fowlie, Department of Romance Languages, Duke University, 1967; 1976 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Charles Fenn (graphologist), 1976 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Samuel French (William Talbot) regarding the Great Campaign and Nobody's Earnest, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Giants in the Earth, 1950-1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Giants in the Earth (University of North Dakota), 1973-1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - John Golden, Inc., February 10, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Foundation (fellowship), March 29, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Jorisland (The First Crocus), 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Mordecai (Max) Gorelik, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - The Great Campaign, 1948-1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Lorna Greene, June 13, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - John Hammond, August 1983 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Harper & Row regarding the record Lullabies and Night Songs, February 1977 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Harper's article "Segregate the Swedes", 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Jerome Hill, 1958-1971 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Hofstra University, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Larry Hugo - Ludi Claire, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Institute of International Education, 1960-1963 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Institute for outdoor drama (Promised Valley), June 1970 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Johnson High School, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Robert Edmond Jones, 1942-1949 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Richard Kaplan (of Richard Kaplan Productions), 1961-1966 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Adna Karnes regarding Riley Randall, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Elia Kazan, October 25-30, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Kilgo Run, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - The Kilgo Run; miscellaneous, 1941-1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Knock on Wood correspondence, 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Little, Brown & Company; Alan D. Williams, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Joe Losey, RKO pictures, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Lectures, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Dai-Keong Lee, 1973-1978 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Howard Lindsay regarding Life with Father, 1964; 1966 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - The Edward Mac Dowell Association, Inc., 1963-1967 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Archibald MacLeish, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Ronald Martinetti (James Dean), 1973 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Elizabeth Marton, agent, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Harris Masterson (Theatrical Productions), 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Marion McPartland, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - In memoriam, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    In memoriam for Bob Porterfield of Barter Theatre and Stanley Young (playwright); Jerome Hill, film editor of Louis W. and Maud Hill Family Foundation.
  - Mitch Miller regarding the Truth About Windmills, 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - The Miracle of Growth, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous business correspondence, 1933-1978 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1983-1988 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous personal correspondence, 1967-1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Douglas Moore, Columbia University, CCNY, 1953-1967 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - William Morris Agency, 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Letters from readers regarding the New Yorker stories, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - The New Yorker magazine, 1959-1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - New York Public Library (Lincoln Center) regarding gift to library, 1942-1976 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Nobody's Earnest, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Nobody's Earnest (Ethan Ayer), September 9, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Nobody's Earnest correspondence, 1978-1983 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - New York University, Dr. Edna Levine and Carl Smith, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Nolan-Yellin Productions, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Ossaban Island Project, 1968-1976 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Gregory Peck, 1948-1953 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Bob Porterfield, Barter Theatre, 1964-1971 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Post college, 1962-1966 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Nikos Psacharopoulos, Executive Director, Williamstown Theatre, 1972-1976 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - The Richmond Organization, 1962-1977 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Martin and Adele Ritt, 20th Century Fox, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Paul Rogers, 1971-1974 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Norman Rosten, 1973-1976 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Wolfgang Roth, May 21, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - St. Paul Opera House, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Eddie Sauter, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Oscar Serlin Productions, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Alan Schneider, 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Bruno Skoggard, 1971-1975 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Fred Stewart, 1945-1962 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Beatrice Straight, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Beatrice Straight Rosenthal "Snow Queen" project, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Tanglewood, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Theatre, Inc. (resignation from), 1947 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Trinity College - educational exchange grant, 1958-1966 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - T.V. suggestions, "The Trial of William Penn" etc., 1952 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - The Truth About Windmills, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - University of Utah, nomination for award, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - University of Utah, Promised Valley, Crawford Gates, 1956-1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The Viking Press, Mrs. Anne Hancock, June 6, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Overture at the University of Virginia, 1940-1963 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Vista magazine "Lincoln Country", 1965 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Max von Sydow, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Dave Wasserman, 1966-1974 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Correspondence regarding Man of La Mancha and Cuckoo's Nest and Montparnasse.
  - A. Watkins, Inc. (agency), "Hot Air, Fiddlesticks and Baloney", 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Wesleyan University, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Western Star, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - E. B. White, November 2, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Robert Whitehead, February 25, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Alec Wilder, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Thornton Wilder regarding sponsorship for Guggenheim, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Williamstown project regarding On Hemlock Brook, October 1953 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - The Wind Blows Free, 1948-1968 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Wisconsin Center for Theatre Research, 1962-1968 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Audrey Wood, 1942-1978 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Audrey Wood regarding Down in the Valley, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Yale, 1970-1974 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Ziegler-Hellman and Ross regarding Christmas program, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Series 2: Musical Scores, 1947-1982; (boxes 5-6, 44-46)
  Series 2: Musical Scores (1947-1982) is arranged alphabetically by title and comprises sheet music and lyrics written by Arnold Sundgaard. Some of the music is published under title of play and some are handwritten music for individual songs. Plays included are: Buddy, Knock on Wood, Of Love Remembered, Promised Valley, Cumberland Fair: A Jamboree, Down in the Valley, Gallantry, Sunday Excursion, The Lowland Sea, The Lonesome Dove. About one-third of the material is in oversize boxes.
  - Buddy, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
    Original draft to Arnold Sundgaard from Louis Bellson.
  - Knock on Wood score, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - O Wonderous Earth; Many a Gal Have I Passed By (sheet music and lyrics), undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Of Love Remembered, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Promised Valley sheet music (loose and published), 1947; 1961 (Oversize 44)
  - Published scores, 1948 - 1958 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Cumberland Fair: A Jamboree; Down in the Valley; Gallantry.
  - Published scores, 1950s-1960s (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Kittiwake Island; The Lowland Sea; The Greenfield Christmas Tree.
  - Published scores, 1950s (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Sunday Excursion; The Lowland Sea; The Lonesome Dove.
  - Published scores, 1952-1959 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Shepherds, Rise; Gepäck träger Blues (The Baggage Room Blues); An Axe, an Apple and a Buckskin Jacket; Long John; There's Doubt in my Mind (but hope in my heart); Where do you go?
  - Sheet music, 1950s; undated (Oversize 45)
    Sheet music for "The Earth Turns Around Without Me Now", "Where do we come from? What are we? Where do we go from here?", "The Ocracoke School song", "That Thing I'm Looking For", "I'm Free at Last", "I Know my Star is There Somewhere", "Hurry Home", "Here Comes Tomorrow", "The Greenfield Christmas Tree", "The Lowland Sea", "Cumberland Fair".
  - Sheet music, undated (Oversize 46)
    Includes the songs: "No Country Boys Allowed in Chicago", "Laurel, Mississippi (Ora's)", "Here Tiz", "You Can Keep Countin' on me", "Isabella", "Jazz", "The Pie Mau", "On That Judgement Day", "Ora's Song", "Dig Down Deep", "Buddy's Blues", "Blues Singer", "By Surprise", "How do you Buy Back a Dream", "Opening Act part II".
  - The Wind Blows Free sheet music, circa 1970s (Oversize 46)
- Series 3: Newspaper Clippings, 1935-1976; (boxes 6-8, 43)
  Series 3: Newspaper Clippings (1935-1976) is arranged alphabetically by title and includes primarily newspaper and magazine clippings relating to play productions and writings authored by Sundgaard, as well as scrapbooks, programs, ephemera, and some photographs. Two scrapbooks, one about Of Love Remembered, the other about Federal Theatre Project productions, Spirochete and Everywhere I Roam, are housed in oversize boxes.
  - Brigham, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Press releases, newspaper and magazine clippings.
  - Buddy Biloxi (newspaper clippings), 1955 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Down in the Valley (newspaper clippings), 1940s-1960s (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Everywhere I Roam, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Includes newspaper clippings, program, broadside.
  - Forests of the Night (newspaper clippings, program), 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Gallantry Greenfield Christmas (newspaper clippings), 1962 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Giants in the Earth, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Giants in the Earth (newspaper clippings), April 15, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Giants of the Earth (newspaper clippings), 1974 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Giants in the Earth (newspaper clippings, program), 1951 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - The Great Campaign (newspaper clippings, program), 1945 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Jorislund (The First Crocus), circa 1941 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Includes newspaper and clippings, promotional letters and mailings.
  - The Kilgo Run (newspaper clippings, programs), 1952-1964 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Kittiwake Island, Sunday Excursion, Lowland Sea (newspaper clippings), 1950s (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, 1935-1967 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Montparnasse (newspaper clippings), January 1970 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Nobody's Earnest at Williamstown Theatre (newspaper clippings, ephemera), 1973 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Nobody's Earnest reviews, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Of Love Remembered (newspaper clippings), 1967 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Of Love Remembered scrapbook (brown cover), 1966-1967 (Oversize 43)
    Includes photographs, newspaper clippings, telegrams, and programs about Of Love Remembered, actress Ingrid Thulin, and Forests of the Night premiere in Dublin.
  - On Hemlock Brook (newspaper clippings), 1953 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - The Opening (press release), undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Peer Gynt, Town Hall concerts (newspaper clippings, programs), 1957 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Promised Valley (newspaper clippings), 1950-1971 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Rhapsody (newspaper clippings, program), 1944 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Scrapbook (black cover), 1939-1973 (Oversize 43)
    Mostly newspaper clippings and programs from Federal Theatre Project productions of Spirochete and Everywhere I Roam. Also contains newspaper article and sign relating to Sundgaard's later career.
  - Spirochete / Everywhere I Roam scrapbook (cover), 1938 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Spirochete / Everywhere I Roam scrapbook, 1938-1939 (Box 7, Folder 18)